let Questions = [
    [{
        question: "Q1: What is the full Form of HTML?",
        option1: "Hyper Text Markup Language",
        option2: "Hyper Text Message Language",
        option3: "Hyper Transport Machanisem Line",
        option4: "High Transiction Machine Lay",
        ans: "Hyper Text Markup Language"
    },
    {
        question: "Q2: What is the head tag in html?",
        option1: "<heading></heading>",
        option2: "<h1></h1>",
        option3: "<p></p>",
        option4: "<i></i>",
        ans: "<h1></h1>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q3: tag of span?",
        option1: "<sp></sp>",
        option2: "<span></span>",
        option3: "<cepan></cepan>",
        option4: "all of the above",
        ans: "<span></span>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q4: Anchor tag use?",
        option1: "<i></i>",
        option2: "<a></a>",
        option3: "<a href='#'></a>",
        option4: "<src></src>",
        ans: "<a href='#'></a>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q5: Paraghrap tag in html?",
        option1: "<p></p>",
        option2: "<par></par>",
        option3: "<paraghrap></paraghrap>",
        option4: "none of these",
        ans: "<p></p>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q6: image tag in html?",
        option1: "<imag></imag>",
        option2: "<img><img>",
        option3: "<img></img>",
        option4: "all of the above",
        ans: "<img></img>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q7: Why we use HTML?",
        option1: "for Cascading style",
        option2: "for structure on a browser",
        option3: "for backend query",
        option4: "none of these",
        ans: "for structure on a browser"
    },
    {
        question: "Q8: tabel create in html?",
        option1: "<table><tr><td>",
        option2: "<tr><td><table>",
        option3: "<header><tbody><tfooter>",
        option4: "first one",
        ans: "<table><tr><td>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q9: HTML Correct div tag?",
        option1: "<dev></dev>",
        option2: "<div></div>",
        option3: "both of the above",
        option4: "first of the above",
        ans: "<div></div>"
    },
    {
        question: "Q10: html strong tag uses?",
        option1: "<b></b>",
        option2: "<em></em>",
        option3: "all of the above",
        option4: "none of these",
        ans: "none of these"
    }],
    [{
        question: "Q1: What does CSS stand for?",
        option1: "Cascading Style Sheets",
        option2: "Colourful Style Shine",
        option3: "Casgat style sheets",
        option4: "Correct Style Shay",
        ans: "Cascading Style Sheets"
    },
    {
        question: "Q2: Which of the following is a way to associate styles with your HTML document?",
        option1: "Embedded CSS - The",
        option2: "Inline CSS - The style Attribute",
        option3: "Both of the above",
        option4: "None of the above.",
        ans: "Both of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Q3: Which of the following is correct about Hex Code format of CSS colors?",
        option1: "The first two digits(RR) represent a red value.",
        option2: "The next two are a green value(GG).",
        option3: "The last are the blue value(BB).",
        option4: "all of the above",
        ans: "all of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Q4: Which of the following property is used to set the background image of an element?",
        option1: " background-color",
        option2: "background-image",
        option3: " background-repeat",
        option4: " background-position",
        ans: "background-image"
    },
    {
        question: "Q5: Which of the following property is used to add or subtract space between the letters that make up a word?",
        option1: "color",
        option2: "direction",
        option3: "letter-spacing",
        option4: "word-spacing",
        ans: "letter-spacing"
    },
    {
        question: "Q6:Which of the following property of a anchor element signifies visited hyperlinks?",
        option1: ":link",
        option2: ":visited",
        option3: " :hover",
        option4: ":active",
        ans: ":visited"
    },
    {
        question: "Q7: Which of the following property specifies the width of a border?",
        option1: ":border-color",
        option2: ":border-style",
        option3: ":border-width",
        option4: ":border-bottom-color",
        ans: ":border-width"
    },
    {
        question: "Q8: Which of the following property changes the color of left border?",
        option1: " :border-top-color",
        option2: ":border-left-color",
        option3: " :border-right-color",
        option4: ":border-bottom-color",
        ans: ":border-left-color"
    },
    {
        question: "Q9: Which of the following property specifies the bottom margin of an element?",
        option1: " :margin",
        option2: " :margin-bottom",
        option3: " :margin-top",
        option4: ":margin-left",
        ans: ":margin-bottom"
    },
    {
        question: "Q10: Which of the following value of cursor shows it as crosshair or plus sign?",
        option1: "crosshair",
        option2: " default",
        option3: "pointer",
        option4: " move",
        ans: "crosshair"
    }],
    [{
        question: "Q1:Which of the following is a disadvantage of using JavaScript?",
        option1: "Client-side JavaScript does not allow the reading or writing of files.",
        option2: "JavaScript can not be used for Networking applications because there is no such support available.",
        option3: " JavaScript doesn't have any multithreading or multiprocess capabilities.",
        option4: "All of the above",
        ans: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Q2:Can you pass a anonymous function as an argument to another function?",
        option1: "true",
        option2: "false",
        option3: "error",
        option4: "undifined",
        ans: "true"
    },
    {
        question: "Q3: Which of the following is correct about callbacks?",
        option1: " A callback is a plain JavaScript function passed to some method as an argument or option.",
        option2: "Some callbacks are just events, called to give the user a chance to react when a certain state is triggered.",
        option3: "none of the above",
        option4: "all of the above",
        ans: "all of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Q4: Which built-in method sorts the elements of an array?",
        option1: "changeOrder(order)",
        option2: " order()",
        option3: "sort()",
        option4: "None of the above.",
        ans: "sort()"
    },
    {
        question: "Q5: Which of the following function of String object returns the character at the specified index??",
        option1: "charAt()",
        option2: " charCodeAt()",
        option3: " concat()",
        option4: "indexOf()",
        ans: "charAt()"
    },
    {
        question: "Q6:  Which of the following function of String object executes the search for a match between a regular expression and a specified string??",
        option1: " concat()",
        option2: " match()",
        option3: " replace()",
        option4: "search()",
        ans: "search()"
    },
    {
        question: "Q7:  Which of the following function of String object returns the primitive value of the specified object?",
        option1: "toLocaleUpperCase()",
        option2: "toUpperCase()",
        option3: " toString()",
        option4: "valueOf()",
        ans: "valueOf()"
    },
    {
        question: "Q8:  Which of the following function of Array object returns a new array comprised of this array joined with other array(s) and/or value(s)?",
        option1: " concat()",
        option2: "pop()",
        option3: "push()",
        option4: " some()",
        ans: "concat()"
    },
    {
        question: "Q9:  Which of the following function of Array object returns true if every element in this array satisfies the provided testing function?",
        option1: "concat()",
        option2: "every()",
        option3: "push()",
        option4: "some()",
        ans: "every()"
    },
    {
        question: "Q10: Which of the following function of Array object applies a function simultaneously against two values of the array (from right-to-left) as to reduce it to a single value?",
        option1: " pop()",
        option2: " push()",
        option3: "reduce()",
        option4: "reduceRight()",
        ans: "reduceRight()"
    }],
    [{
        question: "Q1: Which of the following is the correct name of React.js?",
        option1: "React",
        option2: "React.js",
        option3: "ReactJS",
        option4: "All of the above",
        ans: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Q2:  Which of the following are the advantages of React.js?",
        option1: "React.js can increase the application's performance with Virtual DOM.",
        option2: "React.js is easy to integrate with other frameworks such as Angular, BackboneJS since it is only a view library.",
        option3: "React.js can render both on client and server side.",
        option4: "All of the above",
        ans: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Q3: Which of the following is not a disadvantage of React.js?",
        option1: "React.js has only a view layer. We have put your code for Ajax requests, events and so on.",
        option2: "The library of React.js is pretty large.",
        option3: "The JSX in React.js makes code easy to read and write",
        option4: "The learning curve can be steep in React.js.",
        ans: "The JSX in React.js makes code easy to read and write"
    },
    {
        question: "Q4:Which of the following command is used to install create-react-app?",
        option1: "npm install -g create-react-app",
        option2: "npm install create-react-app",
        option3: "npm install -f create-react-app",
        option4: "install -g create-react-app",
        ans: "npm install -g create-react-app"
    },
    {
        question: "Q5: What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
        option1: "Original DOM",
        option2: "Virtual DOM",
        option3: "Both A and B.",
        option4: "none of these",
        ans: "Virtual DOM"
    },
    {
        question: "Q6: A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
        option1: "Constructor",
        option2: "Class",
        option3: "Object",
        option4: "DataObject",
        ans: "Class"
    },
    {
        question: "Q7:Which of the following acts as the input of a class-based component?",
        option1: "Class",
        option2: "Factory",
        option3: "Render",
        option4: "Props",
        ans: "Props"
    },
    {
        question: "Q8: Which of the following keyword is used to create a class inheritance?",
        option1: "Create",
        option2: "Inherits",
        option3: "Extends",
        option4: "This",
        ans: "Extends"
    },
    {
        question: "Q9:  What is the default port where webpack-server runs?",
        option1: "3000",
        option2: "8080",
        option3: "3030",
        option4: "6060",
        ans: "8080"
    },
    {
        question: "Q10: What is the declarative way to render a dynamic list of components based on values in an array?",
        option1: "Using the reduce array method",
        option2: "Using the <Each /> component",
        option3: "Using the Array.map() method",
        option4: "With a for/while loop",
        ans: "Using the Array.map() method"
    }],
    [{
        question: "Q1:Command to create NextJS app?",
        option1: "npx new create-next-app@latest",
        option2: "npx create-next-app@latest",
        option3: "npx new app create-next-app@latest",
        option4: "None of these",
        ans: "npx create-next-app@latest"
    },
    {
        question: "Q2: on which Port NextJS app runs?",
        option1: "5000",
        option2: "3000",
        option3: "7000",
        option4: "None of these",
        ans: "3000"
    },
    {
        question: "Q3: SSR stands for?",
        option1: "Server static resources",
        option2: "Server side response",
        option3: "Server Side Rendering",
        option4: "all of the above",
        ans: "Server Side Rendering"
    },
    {
        question: "Q4:  Why 'next/link' is used in NextJS?",
        option1: "navigations to another routes",
        option2: "image processing",
        option3: "text formatting",
        option4: "None of these",
        ans: "navigations to another routes"
    },
    {
        question: "Q5: NextJS is developed by?",
        option1: "Facebook",
        option2: "Google",
        option3: "Vercel",
        option4: "none of these",
        ans: "Vercel"
    },
    {
        question: "Q6: Command to start next.js project in development mode?",
        option1: "npm run",
        option2: "npm run dev",
        option3: "npm start build",
        option4: "all of the above",
        ans: "npm run dev"
    },
    {
        question: "Q7: Command to build an application for production in Next.js??",
        option1: "npm run build",
        option2: "npm build",
        option3: "npm run",
        option4: "none of these",
        ans: "npm run build"
    },
    {
        question: "Q8:  Why 'next/image' used in NextJS?",
        option1: "Image processing",
        option2: "Image Linking",
        option3: "Image optimization",
        option4: "first one",
        ans: "Image optimization"
    },
    {
        question: "Q9: Upgrade React version to latest in Next.JS app?",
        option1: "npm upgrade react@latest react-dom@latest",
        option2: "npm install react@latest react-dom@latest",
        option3: "npm reinstall react@latest react-dom@latest",
        option4: "first of the above",
        ans: "npm install react@latest react-dom@latest"
    },
    {
        question: "Q10: Nextjs is a:",
        option1: "Library",
        option2: "reactjs framework",
        option3: "javascript Framework",
        option4: "none of these",
        ans: "javascript Framework"
    }]
]

let count = 0;
function loader(fromOption) {
    document.getElementById("myQuestions").innerText = Questions[fromOption][count].question;
    document.getElementById("myPara1").innerText = Questions[fromOption][count].option1;
    document.getElementById("myPara2").innerText = Questions[fromOption][count].option2;
    document.getElementById("myPara3").innerText = Questions[fromOption][count].option3;
    document.getElementById("myPara4").innerText = Questions[fromOption][count].option4;
    
    document.getElementById("inputDisable1").addEventListener("change", function(){
        document.getElementById("myButton").disabled = false;
    })
    document.getElementById("inputDisable2").addEventListener("change", function(){
        document.getElementById("myButton").disabled = false;
    })
    document.getElementById("inputDisable3").addEventListener("change", function(){
        document.getElementById("myButton").disabled = false;
    })
    document.getElementById("inputDisable4").addEventListener("change", function(){
        document.getElementById("myButton").disabled = false;
    })
    
    
    document.getElementById("myButton").disabled = true;
    count = count + 1;
    if(count === Questions[fromOption].length - 1) {
        clicker0(fromOption);
    }
    
    if(count === Questions[fromOption].length) {
        count = count - 1;
        document.getElementById("myDiv1").remove();
        let body = document.body;
        let lastDiv = document.createElement("div");
        let lastDivChild = document.createElement("div");
        lastDivChild.setAttribute("id", "lastDivChildId");
        body.appendChild(lastDivChild);
        let Heading = document.createElement("h2");
        let div1 = document.createElement("div");
        let div2 = document.createElement("div");
        let div3 = document.createElement("div");
        let div4 = document.createElement("div");
        let input1 = document.createElement("input");
        input1.setAttribute("id", "inputDisable1");
        input1.setAttribute("type", "radio");
        input1.setAttribute("name", "myquize");
        let input2 = document.createElement("input");
        input2.setAttribute("id", "inputDisable2");
        input2.setAttribute("type", "radio");
        input2.setAttribute("name", "myquize");
        let input3 = document.createElement("input");
        input3.setAttribute("id", "inputDisable3");
        input3.setAttribute("type", "radio");
        input3.setAttribute("name", "myquize");
        let input4 = document.createElement("input");
        input4.setAttribute("id", "inputDisable4");
        input4.setAttribute("type", "radio");
        input4.setAttribute("name", "myquize");
        let lable1 = document.createElement("label");
        lable1.setAttribute("for","inputDisable1");
        let lable2 = document.createElement("label");
        lable2.setAttribute("for","inputDisable2");
        let lable3 = document.createElement("label");
        lable3.setAttribute("for","inputDisable3");
        let lable4 = document.createElement("label");
        lable4.setAttribute("for","inputDisable4");
        Heading.appendChild(document.createTextNode(Questions[fromOption][count].question));
        lable1.appendChild(document.createTextNode(Questions[fromOption][count].option1))
        lable2.appendChild(document.createTextNode(Questions[fromOption][count].option2))
        lable3.appendChild(document.createTextNode(Questions[fromOption][count].option3))
        lable4.appendChild(document.createTextNode(Questions[fromOption][count].option4))
        div1.appendChild(input1);
        div2.appendChild(input2);
        div3.appendChild(input3);
        div4.appendChild(input4);
        div1.appendChild(lable1);
        div2.appendChild(lable2);
        div3.appendChild(lable3);
        div4.appendChild(lable4);
        lastDivChild.appendChild(Heading);
        lastDivChild.appendChild(div1);
        lastDivChild.appendChild(div2);
        lastDivChild.appendChild(div3);
        lastDivChild.appendChild(div4);
        lastDivChild.appendChild(lastDiv);
        
        let newBtn =  document.createElement("button");
        newBtn.setAttribute("id","myNewBtn"); 
        
        newBtn.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Submit Quize"));
        lastDiv.appendChild(newBtn)
        lastDivChild.appendChild(lastDiv);
        newBtn.addEventListener("click", function() {
            clicker1(fromOption)
            resultFunc()
        })
    }
}

// yeha say aj
function firstCLicker (){
 if(document.getElementById("html").checked){
    let myDiv = document.getElementById("myDiv1");
    let myButton = document.createElement("button");
    myButton.setAttribute("id","myButton");
    myButton.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Next"));
    myDiv.appendChild(myButton);
    myButton.addEventListener("click", function(){
        loader(0);
        clicker(0);
    })
    document.getElementById("myDiv1").style.display = "block";
    document.querySelector(".mainContainer").style.display = "none";
    loader(0);
 }

 else if(document.getElementById("css").checked){
    let myDiv = document.getElementById("myDiv1");
    let myButton = document.createElement("button");
    myButton.setAttribute("id","myButton");
    myButton.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Next"));
    myDiv.appendChild(myButton);
    myButton.addEventListener("click", function(){
        loader(1);
        clicker(1)
    })
    document.getElementById("myDiv1").style.display = "block";
    document.querySelector(".mainContainer").style.display = "none";
    loader(1);
 }

 else if(document.getElementById("Javascript").checked){
    let myDiv = document.getElementById("myDiv1");
    let myButton = document.createElement("button");
    myButton.setAttribute("id","myButton");
    myButton.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Next"));
    myDiv.appendChild(myButton);
    myButton.addEventListener("click", function(){
        loader(2);
        clicker(2)
    })
    document.getElementById("myDiv1").style.display = "block";
    document.querySelector(".mainContainer").style.display = "none";
  loader(2);
 }

 else if(document.getElementById("Reactjs").checked){
    let myDiv = document.getElementById("myDiv1");
    let myButton = document.createElement("button");
    myButton.setAttribute("id","myButton");
    myButton.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Next"));
    myDiv.appendChild(myButton);
    myButton.addEventListener("click", function(){
        loader(3);
        clicker(3)
    })
    document.getElementById("myDiv1").style.display = "block";
    document.querySelector(".mainContainer").style.display = "none";
 loader(3);
 }

 else if(document.getElementById("Nextjs").checked){
    let myDiv = document.getElementById("myDiv1");
    let myButton = document.createElement("button");
    myButton.setAttribute("id","myButton");
    myButton.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Next"));
    myDiv.appendChild(myButton);
    myButton.addEventListener("click", function(){
        loader(4);
        clicker(4)
    })
    document.getElementById("myDiv1").style.display = "block";
    document.querySelector(".mainContainer").style.display = "none";
    loader(4);
 }
}

// yeha tak

// loader();

let one;
let two;
let three;
let four;
let result = 0;
function clicker(myVal) {
    one = Questions[myVal][count - 2].option1;
    two = Questions[myVal][count - 2].option2;
    three = Questions[myVal][count - 2].option3;
    four = Questions[myVal][count - 2].option4;
    if (document.getElementById("inputDisable1").checked) {
        if (one.includes(Questions[myVal][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable2").checked) {
        if (two.includes(Questions[myVal][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable3").checked) {
        if (three.includes(Questions[myVal][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable4").checked) {
        if (four.includes(Questions[myVal][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
   
}

function clicker0(fromOption) {
    one = Questions[fromOption][count - 2].option1;
    two = Questions[fromOption][count - 2].option2;
    three = Questions[fromOption][count - 2].option3;
    four = Questions[fromOption][count - 2].option4;
    console.log(one)
    if (document.getElementById("inputDisable1").checked) {
        if (one.includes(Questions[fromOption][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable2").checked) {
        if (two.includes(Questions[fromOption][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable3").checked) {
        if (three.includes(Questions[fromOption][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable4").checked) {
        if (four.includes(Questions[fromOption][count - 2].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
}

function clicker1(fromOption) {
    one = Questions[fromOption][Questions.length - 1].option1;
    two = Questions[fromOption][Questions.length - 1].option2;
    three = Questions[fromOption][Questions.length - 1].option3;
    four = Questions[fromOption][Questions.length - 1].option4;
    console.log(one)
    if (document.getElementById("inputDisable1").checked) {
        if (one.includes(Questions[fromOption][Questions[fromOption].length - 1].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable2").checked) {
        if (two.includes(Questions[fromOption][Questions[fromOption].length - 1].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable3").checked) {
        if (three.includes(Questions[fromOption][Questions[fromOption].length - 1].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
    else if (document.getElementById("inputDisable4").checked) {
        if (four.includes(Questions[fromOption][Questions[fromOption].length - 1].ans)) {
            result = result + 1;
        }
    }
}

function resultFunc() {
    document.getElementById("lastDivChildId").remove();
    let resultBody = document.body;
    let resultDiv = document.createElement("div");
    resultDiv.setAttribute("id", "resultDivId")
    let heading1 = document.createElement("h1");
    heading1.style.textAlign= "center";
    let resultDivChild = document.createElement("div");
    let myPara = document.createElement("h2");
    myPara.setAttribute("id", "myParalast")
    resultDivChild.appendChild(myPara);
    resultDivChild.setAttribute("id","resultId");
    resultBody.appendChild(resultDiv);
    if(result >= 7) {
        heading1.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Congratulation You Are Passed"));
        heading1.style.color = "#3f8d3f";
        resultDivChild.style.border = "6px #3f8d3f solid";
    }
    else {
        heading1.appendChild(document.createTextNode("Sorry ! You Are Failed"));
        resultDivChild.style.border = "6px #f00 solid";
        heading1.style.color = "#f00";
    }
    resultDiv.appendChild(heading1);
    resultDiv.appendChild(resultDivChild);
    resultDivChild.appendChild(document.createTextNode(result+ "0%"));
}